Guide to the Nathaniel and Thomas Shaw Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Papers of Nathaniel and Thomas Shaw letters, accounts, bills, receipts, notes, orders, etc.
  - Accounts
    - Record no. 38, 1769-1777 (Box 24)
      Listing cargoes of a number of vessels on specified voyages and disposition of same to various customers. There is a record, May 1776-Jan. 1777, of supplies, including guns and powder, received from the Continental government, and the disposition of these supplies to various individuals and forts. An inventory of "Goods received on shore" from a prize ship captured by the ship Andrea Doria also appears. Scattered through the book are ledger entries to various people. (1 vol.-33x21 cm., sewed in paper cover)
    - Ledger no. 39, 1776-1778 (Box 24)
      Containing accounts of Nathaniel Shaw's duties as Continental agent for the colony of Connecticut, in fitting and supplying vessels of the Continental and Connecticut Navy, caring for sick sailors, disposing of prize vessels and their cargoes, and as agent of supply for the Secret Committee of Connecticut. [See biography of Shaw in D.A.B.]. Most of the entries are for outfitting and supplying ships of the Continental and Connecticut Navies, including the Alfred, Cabot, Andrea Doria, Hampden, Trumbull, Fly, Resistance, Schuyler, and Continent. Shaw was rewarded with a 5 per cent commission on materials furnished to these ships, and on p. 53-54 there is an account with "The Honorable Marine Committee" of Philadelphia for settlement of the various charges incurred in this capacity.
      Pages 8-11, 16 contain accounts of payments made by Shaw to townpeople of New London for room, board, and care of seamen ill from small pox or wounded in action around the Bahamas under Capt. Esek Hopkins, commander of the Continental Navy. [See: New London County Historical Society Collections, v; 2, p.46-47.]
      On pp. 32-37 are accounts of sales of prizes, showing the distribution of proceeds: Shaw's commission, 1/3 of the remainder to the capturers, and 2/3 to the government. The proceeds from these sales are charged off on pp. 53-54 against the expenses incurred from outfitting the government ships.
      In inverse and reverse order in the back of the book are charges for goods and services to the Ordinance Store of New York, the Marine Committee of Philadelphia, Col. Richmon's Regiment, the Continental Board of "Warr", the Continental Navy Board, Forts at Groton, Mamecock, and Stonington, and to General Washington, Joseph Trumbull, John Michel (the last including a charge to General Gates), and Barnabus Dean, procurer on the Secret Committee. (1 vol. - 28x18 cm., sewed in paper cover)
    - Record no. 40, 1757 May (Box 24)
      The sale at public vendue at Newport, R.I. of the cargo of the prize ship La Jean Teresa which was captured by the sloop Little Rogers. There are 9 pp. of entries for the sale of sugar and coffee, listed by numbered lots with price and name of purchaser for each. (1 vol. - 34x20 cm., sewed in paper cover)
    - Unnumbered ledger, 1760-1766 (Box 24)
      Accounts with vessels for the sale of rope, cable, marlin, yarn, planks, turpentine, hay, candles, corn, salt, beef, rum etc. (1 vol. - 30x16 cm.)
    - Unnumbered letterbook, vellum covers, 1765-1786 (Box 24)
      (This is the "Commercial letterbook" referred to in Rogers.)
    - Papers removed from account books, undated (Box 24)
    - 9 negatives of 9 items [not filmed], undated (Box 24)
  - Oversized material (Box 34, Folder 1-8)
- Name and Subject Cards with Item Numbers and Order Books
  - Name and Subject Cards with Item Numbers (Box 33)
    - A-F (Box 29)
    - G-M (Box 30)
    - N-V (Box 31)
    - W-Y (Box 32)
  - Order books (Box 33)